<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Translation | Allen's Technical Blog.]]></title>
  <link href="http://allen501pc.github.io/blog/categories/translation/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://allen501pc.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-21T12:58:09+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://allen501pc.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Allen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Translation] Yahoo to buy Tumblr for $1.1bn]]></title>
    <link href="http://allen501pc.github.io/blog/2013/05/21/yahoo-to-buy-tumblr-for-1-dollars-dot-1bn/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-21T12:36:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://allen501pc.github.io/blog/2013/05/21/yahoo-to-buy-tumblr-for-1-dollars-dot-1bn</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h4><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-22591026">The original post</a></h4>

<p>Yahoo to buy Tumblr for $1.1bn</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Yahoo has agreed a deal to buy New York-based blogging service Tumblr for $1.1bn (￡723m; 857m euros) in cash.
Yahoo&rsquo;s chief executive Marissa Mayer said that as part of its promise &ldquo;not to screw it up&rdquo;, Tumblr would operate independently.<br/>
David Karp, will continue as chief executive officer of Tumblr.<br/>
The deal is the largest made by Ms Mayer since she took the helm at Yahoo last July, and she described the acquisition as a &ldquo;unique opportunity."<br/>
"On many levels, Tumblr and Yahoo couldn&rsquo;t be more different, but at the same time, they couldn&rsquo;t be more complementary,&rdquo; added Ms Mayer.<br/>
Mr Karp, 26, who owns 25% of the privately-owned company he co-founded with Marco Arment in 2007, said he was &ldquo;elated&rdquo; to have the support of Yahoo.<br/>
&ldquo;Tumblr gets better faster with more resources to draw from,&rdquo; he added. Mr Karp emphasised that neither its aims or team was changing as a result of Yahoo&rsquo;s purchase.</p>

<p>Mobile devices
The $1.1bn price tag for Tumblr represents a significant premium on its $800m valuation when it last raised money from private investors.<br/>
Tumblr&rsquo;s 2012 revenue was just $13m, according to a report by Forbes magazine, leading analysts to suggest Yahoo had overpaid for the deal.<br/>
&ldquo;Even if revenue was $100 million, it means Yahoo paid 10 times revenue,&rdquo; said BGC Financial analyst Colin Gillis. &ldquo;Ten times is what you pay to date the belle of the ball. It&rsquo;s on the outer bands of M&amp;A."<br/>
Tumblr combines elements of blogging with social networking, and its simple design has attracted millions of users since its launch.<br/>
According to its homepage, it now hosts 108 million blogs, with a total of 50.7 billion posts.<br/>
It also has a significant presence on mobile devices.<br/>
But despite its fast-growing user base, it has struggled to make money and has traditionally resisted advertising.<br/>
It said in April 2012 that it would roll out limited use of adverts.<br/>
Ms Mayer said Yahoo would now work with Tumblr to create ads that "are seamless and enhance the user experience&rdquo;.<br/>
Brian Wieser, analyst at Pivotal Research Group, said that the quickest way for Yahoo to boost Tumblr&rsquo;s revenue would be to combine its sales force with the blogging site, but that this would risk alienating users.<br/>
&ldquo;It&rsquo;s not clear that this deal will be favourable from a return-on-capital perspective,&rdquo; Wieser said. &ldquo;One billion [dollars] for one company is a big bet.&rdquo;
Yahoo remains a giant in the internet world, with around 700 million visitors to its website every month. The majority of its revenues come from advertising.
But it has limited mobile reach and lags behind Google in the search engine rankings.<br/>
It also shed more than 1,000 jobs during 2012 and has long been divided over whether it should focus on media content or on tools and technologies.</p>

<hr />

<h4>Vocabularies</h4>

<ol>
<li>screw (vi.) 轉動、吝嗇 (vt.) (用螺旋)操縱, 調節；(用螺釘等)固定(或擰緊)[(+on/onto/to)]；使振作; 鼓舞[(+up)] (n.) 螺絲</li>
<li>acquisition (n.) 獲得, 取得[U]；獲得物[C]</li>
<li>elate (adj.) 得意的、(vt.) 使得意洋洋、使興奮</li>
<li>better faster 更好更快</li>
<li>emphasis 強調</li>
<li>investor (n.) 投資人</li>
<li>revenue (n.) 收入、營收</li>
<li>belle (n.) 美女</li>
</ol>


<hr />

<h4>Grammar</h4>

<ol>
<li>screw sth. up (常作為)砸鍋</li>
</ol>


<h4>Translation</h4>

<p>Yahoo 以11億美元買下Tumblr<br/>
Yahoo 已經以11億美元現金(相當於7.23億英鎊或8.57億歐元)同意購買以紐約為主的部落格服務Tumblr。 <br/>
Yahoo的執行長Marissa Mayer說：「就如同它承諾的一部分『別把它搞砸了』。」，Tumblr會獨立運作。 <br/>
David Karp將續任Tumblr的執行長。這是Mayer女士自去年七月接棒Yahoo有史以來的最大交易案，而她描述此一購案是「大好機會」。
「在許多層面來看，Tumblr與Yahoo不會有太多不同，但同時也不會更為互補。」<br/>
現年26歲的Karp先生，於2007年間，擁有與Marco Arment合夥的私人公司25%的股權，說他對於Yahoo的支援感到「非常得意」。<br/>
「Tumblr隨著更多資源的投入，會變得更好更快來吸引更多的人」他補充道。Karp先生強調當Yahoo付現成定局時，Tumblr的目標或是團隊也不會改變。</p>

<p><strong>行動裝置</strong></p>

<p>標價11億美金對Tumblr而言，代表更顯著的加價，私人投資者之前曾加價達8億美元。<br/>
根據富比士雜誌報導，Tumblr在2012年的收入只有1,300萬美元，首席分析師暗示Yahoo對此交易案多付了太多錢。「即使收入僅有1億美元，表示Yahoo付了10倍的收入」BGC財經分析師Colin Gillis說道。「十倍好比你可以跟球賽美女約會。它是企業購併的例外。」  <br/>
Tumblr把社群網路與部落格元素作結合，自它上線以來，其簡單設計已經吸引了上百萬名使用者。
根據它的首頁顯示，現有1億800萬個部落格，共有507億篇文章。<br/>
它在行動裝置上也有值得注意的存在感。
但除了快速成長的使用者基礎，它面臨賺錢與傳統上反廣告的困窘。<br/>
在2012年四月即公告將移除廣告的限制。<br/>
Mayer女士說Yahoo將與Tumblr合作，建立無縫廣告與強化使用者體驗。
關鍵研究社群的分析師Brain Wieser說，Yahoo強化Tumblr營收的最快方法是結合與部落格網址結合它自己的銷售力，但將遭受使用者流失的風險。<br/>
「從投資報酬率觀點來看，無法清楚得知這是否有利。」Wieser說道。「10億對於一家公司來說是個大賭注」。
Yahoo仍是個網路巨人，每月約7億的瀏覽量。其主要營收來自廣告。
但是它那有限的行動觸角，在網路搜尋引擎的排名中，仍落後於Google。<br/>
在2012年間，它也取消超過1,000個職位，已有很長一段時間處於是否該注重媒體內容或是科技工具的意見分歧中。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Translation] Walk with the locals in Mumbai]]></title>
    <link href="http://allen501pc.github.io/blog/2013/05/19/translation-walk-with-the-locals-in-mumbai/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-19T03:15:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://allen501pc.github.io/blog/2013/05/19/translation-walk-with-the-locals-in-mumbai</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<!--more-->


<h4><a href="http://www.bbc.com/travel/blog/20130515-walk-with-the-locals-in-mumbai">The Original Post</a>:</h4>

<p>The secret to understanding a teeming metropolis lies in exploring its neighbourhoods. It is in these slices of life that a big city’s fast pace slows down and its true nature is revealed.</p>

<p>Mumbai’s first set of world-renowned Jane Jacobs walks (organised in memory of the American author and urban activist) attempts to encapsulate this experience through sojourns to three parts of the city – Mazagaon, Bandra and Juhu – where residents and visitors can see how the local community functions.</p>

<p>Held around the time of Jacob’s birthday in early May, the free walks are a programme promoted by the nonprofit Center for the Living City. Honouring her vital work on urban studies and saving neighbourhoods, anyone can host a Jane Jacobs walk; the only requirement is passion for the city they live in.</p>

<p>The 12 May walk Metamorphosis of Mazagaon, organised by Kavita Gonsalves for the non-profit Urban Design Collective, took walkers around the evolving Mazagaon area of south Mumbai, where colonial Bombay grapples with contemporary Mumbai in its pre-Portuguese-era homes, Goan community clubs and glassy skyscrapers.</p>

<p>The upcoming 19 May Markets of Bandra walk, organised by entrepreneur Shormishta Mukherjee, will delve into the smells, sights and sounds of the bustling community markets in north Mumbai’s Bandra neighbourhood. “Markets are places where people meet and interact and I wanted to share the vibrancy of these spaces,” Mukherjee explained.</p>

<p>Starting at St Andrews Church at 6 pm, the stroll will explore the traditional fishing village of Chimbai, pause for a taste of delicious mince puffs and nankhatais (Indian cookies) at the old bakeries on Hill Road and wind its way into the 400-year-old East Indian Catholic village of Ranwarwith – its Portuguese cottages roofed with Mangalore tiles. The stroll gets eclectic on Chapel Road, where the artsy Wall Project – an innovative graffiti collective – took root, before heading towards Bazaar Road, where a thriving local market, a mosque, temple and church coexist in the same space. Limited to 12 people, registration is via email.</p>

<p>The motive behind the 16 June Juhu walk, according to organiser Pallavi Srivastava of non-profit Urban Vision is “the need to improve the city’s walkability, encourage cleanliness and provide freedom from car-centric mobility in Mumbai”.</p>

<p>Open to everyone, including those on bicycles, in wheelchairs and seniors and children, the walk will begin at 5:30 pm and end around 7:30 pm at Juhu beach, turning into the broad avenue of Linking Road and cutting through laidback Khar, a leafy suburb adjacent to Juhu. The last leg will take participants to the Bandra (Bandstand) and Carter road promenades, which buzz with a colourful mix of skaters, fisher folk, musicians, vendors, young couples, runners, bikers and perhaps even a Bollywood star. Participation is limited to 20 to 25 people and you can sign up on the Facebook page.
Sharon Fernandes is the Mumbai Localite for BBC Travel</p>

<hr />

<h4>Vocabularies</h4>

<ol>
<li>teeming (adj.) 擁擠的、熱鬧的、多產的</li>
<li>metropolis (n.) 大都會</li>
<li>pace (n.) 一步、步調</li>
<li>renown (n.) 盛名、聲譽</li>
<li>urban (adj.) 住在都市的、習慣都市生活的</li>
<li>vital (adj.) 充滿活力的、必要的、生死記錄的</li>
<li>colonial (adj.) 殖民地的 (大寫) 殖民時期的 (n.) 殖民地的居民</li>
<li>glassy (adj.) 玻璃的、無表情的</li>
<li>stroll (n.) 散步 (vi./vt.) 閒逛、散步</li>
<li>graffiti (n.) 塗鴉</li>
<li>vibrancy (adj.) 充滿朝氣的、生氣蓬勃的</li>
<li>entrepreneur (n.) 企業家、生意人</li>
<li>thriving (adj.) 繁華的、興盛的、旺盛的</li>
<li>coexist (vi.) 共存</li>
<li>suburb (n.) 市郊</li>
<li>promenade (n.) 正式舞會、散步、此種散步活動的公共區域 (vt.) 悠閒地散步</li>
<li>buzz (vi.) 嗡嗡聲、發出嘈雜聲 (vt.) 低聲說話 (n.) 嗡嗡聲、打電話</li>
<li>skyscraper (n.) 摩天大樓</li>
<li>cleanliness (n.) 清潔、乾淨</li>
<li>sojourn (vi./n.) 逗留、旅居</li>
<li>collective (n.) 集團、共同體</li>
<li>grapple (n.) 格鬥</li>
<li>contemporary (adj.) 當代的</li>
<li>Portuguese (n.) 葡萄牙人、葡萄牙 (adj.) 葡萄牙的</li>
<li>mince (vt.) 剁碎、細碎 (vi.) 碎步行走 (n.) 絞肉</li>
<li>puff (n.) 喘息、一陣風、蒸氣、咻咻聲、煙 (vi.) 噴出 (+from)、喘氣 (vt.) 吹、抽(煙)</li>
<li>cottage 村舍, 小屋, 農舍、別墅</li>
<li>tile (n.) 磁磚</li>
<li>eclectic (adj.) 選擇的、挑選的、不同材料形成的、折衷的</li>
<li>artsy (adj.) [口語]冒充藝術的、裝作愛好藝術的 (=arty)</li>
<li>mosque (n.) 清真寺</li>
<li>wheelchair (n.) 輪椅</li>
<li>avenue (n.) 林蔭大道、手段</li>
<li>broad (adj.) 寬闊的</li>
<li>laid-back (adj.) 從容不迫的</li>
<li>leafy (adj.) 覆有葉子的、多葉的、茂密的</li>
<li>skater (n.) 溜冰者</li>
<li>runner (n.) 賽跑者、推銷員</li>
<li>folks (n.) 人們</li>
</ol>


<hr />

<h4>Grammar</h4>

<p><strong>1. <a href="http://dict.dreye.com/dj/index.php?dw=in%20memory%20of&amp;hidden_code=01&amp;">in memory of sb.</a>  紀念某人</strong></p>

<pre><code>The obelisk was built in memory of those who died for their country.  
這座方尖塔是為了紀念那些為祖國獻身的人而建造的。     
</code></pre>

<p><strong>2. freedom from 免除, 解脫</strong></p>

<pre><code>freedom from hunger  
免於飢餓
</code></pre>

<hr />

<p><strong>Translation</strong><br/>
要了解這個擁擠的都市秘密得去看它的周遭生活環境。秘密在於大城市的快速步調變慢以及一覽無遺的自然景觀。</p>

<p>孟買的第一個知名的景點是Jane Jacobs行走(用來紀念此一美國作者及住在城市的行動者)，藉由逗留在此城市的三大區塊：Mazagaon, Bandra, Juhu(遊客與居民可在此看出當地的社交機能)，將此一景點納入生活體驗中。</p>

<p>在五月初舉行的Jacob生日，自由的Jane Jacobs行走節目由非營利組織生活城市來推動。瞻仰她對於當地學生所付出的工作，任何人都可以舉辦Jane Jacobs行走，唯一的需求是熱愛他們生活的城市。</p>

<p>在5月12日舉辦的Mazagaon Metamorphosis健走活動，由Kavita Gosalves為了非營利組織城市設計團體來籌辦，將帶領行人環繞孟買南部的Mazagaon地區；該地區曾經是古殖民時期龐貝城的格鬥場，近期則是前葡萄牙時期的住家、Goan社交俱樂部以及冷峻的高樓大廈。</p>

<p>而接著在5月19日舉辦的Bandra市場行走活動，由企業家Shormishta Maukherjee所發起，在孟買北端舉辦的該活動將帶入氣味、景觀與市場的吵雜聲。「市場是做為人們見面、互動的地方以及我想分享這些空間活力的地方」Mukherjee解釋道。</p>

<p>晚上6點從聖安卓教堂出發，健走活動將經過傳統漁村Chimbai，中間在Hill路往Bazzaar路的舊麵包店停留，品嘗美味的碎肉香氣與nankhatais(印度餅乾)。且經過400年歷史的東印度天主教村莊Ranwarwith，它那由Mangalore磁磚鋪設而成的葡萄牙別墅屋頂。轉走往Chapel路，那裡有座藝術牆，創新的塗鴉作品都在這邊。走到底，在轉往Bazzar路前，有著繁榮的當地市場、清真寺、寺廟、教堂共存在這邊。此活動最多12人參加，請透過email註冊。</p>

<p>在6月16日的Juhu健走活動的背後動機，根據來自於非營利團體-城市視野的發起人Pallavi Srivastava的說法：「需要改善本城市的行走力，鼓勵清潔、自汽車集中化的行動力中獲得解脫。」 開放給所有人，包含那些騎腳踏車、坐輪椅的人、國中生與小孩等。此一健走活動在下午5:30開始，到7:30左右抵達Juhu海灘，轉往連結道路旁的寬敞林蔭大道，從容不迫地穿過Khar(一個綠葉覆蓋的鄰近Juhu郊區)。最後一段路程將帶參加者到Bandra(Bandstand)與Carter路散步區，此一區域充斥著多元氣息，包含溜冰者、漁夫、音樂人、攤販、年輕夫婦、賽跑者、腳踏車騎士，甚至是寶來塢明星。參賽者上限約20~25人，你可以在Facebook上登記。
註：本文作者 Sharon Fernandes是BBC Travel在孟買的當地人。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
